Guide to the William E. Irwin Photograph Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Portraits of American Indians, circa 1893-1903; Series VIII; 1.25; (1 box)
  - Studio Portraits of Unidentified Individuals
    - Studio portrait in a wall tent of two American Indian men posed sitting and standing, as well as holding bows and arrows, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 614)
      Inscription in negative: "121"
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 615)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting in a chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 616)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting in a chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 617)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian infant in a cradleboard, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 618)
    - Studio portrait of a Kiowa Indian boy posed standing on a chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 619)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed standing, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 620)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed standing with his back to the camera and a foot on a log set piece, wearing a feathered war bonnet and drawing an arrow on a bow, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 621)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and wearing with fur-wrapped braids, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 622)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed standing and leaning with his knee on a fur-draped chair and wearing with fur-wrapped braids, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 623)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and wearing a suit and hat, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 624)
    - Studio bust portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and wearing a suit and hat, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 625)
    - Studio portrait of a white man and an American Indian man posed sitting and wearing suits, the latter also wears a hat, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 626)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and holding a rifle, wearing a fringed buckskin suit and a single feather in his hair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 627)
    - Studio portrait of two American Indian men, probably Comanche Indians, posed sitting and standing, wearing fur hair wraps, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 628)
    - Studio bust portrait of an American Indian man wearing a jacket and hat, as well as wrapped braids, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 629)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing between an American Indian man and American Indian woman posed sitting; the man wears a suit and the women wear shawls, circa 1893-1903; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 9, Folder 630)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and wearing a hat and wrapped braids with an American Indian woman posed standing with an American Indian infant in a cradleboard, circa 1893-1903; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 9, Folder 631)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and wearing a hat and wrapped braids with an American Indian woman posed standing with an American Indian infant in a cradleboard on her back, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 632)
    - Studio portrait of a Comanche Indian man posed sitting and holding a Comanche Indian girl between two Comanche Indian women posed standing; the members of the group all wear winter coats and shawls, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 633)
    - Studio portrait of two Comanche Indian men posed sitting and standing, as well as wearing fur hair wraps, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 634)
    - Studio portrait of three American Indian women, one woman posed sitting between two women posed standing; all of the women wear shawls with floral print patterns, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 635)
    - Studio portrait of three American Indian women posed standing; all of the women wear shawls with floral print patterns, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 636)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and wearing a shawls with stripes and fringe, as well as a large crucifix, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 637)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and holding a light-colored handkerchief, circa 1893-1903; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 9, Folder 638)
      One of the photographic prints is an enlargement of the same image
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and resting her head on her hand, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 639)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and wearing a rope with long tassels around her waist, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 640)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing with her hands behind her neck and wearing a buckskin dress with elk teeth decoration, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 641)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting next to a table and wearing a buckskin dress with elk teeth decoration, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 642)
    - Studio half portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing with her hands behind her neck and wearing a buckskin dress with elk teeth decoration, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 643)
    - Studio half portrait of three American Indian woman posed standing and all wearing buckskin dresses with elk teeth decoration, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 644)
    - Studio portrait of three American Indian woman, one woman posed sitting between two women posed standing, and all wearing buckskin dresses with elk teeth decoration, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 645)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman seated, with one hand near her face, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 646)
    - Studio portrait of two American Indian women posed sitting and standing, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 647)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and wearing a fringed buckskin dress, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 648)
    - Studio portrait of three Kiowa Indian women posed sitting and kneeling, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 649)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and wearing a buckskin dress with elk teeth decoration and fringe, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 650)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 651)
    - Studio portrait of two American Indian women posed sitting and standing, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 652)
    - Studio portrait of two American Indian women posed sitting and standing, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 653)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting and wearing a buckskin dress with elk teeth decoration and fringe, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 654)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and wearing a buckskin dress with elk teeth decoration and fringe, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 655)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed sitting, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 656)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man and woman posed standing, the man holding a hat, identified as possibly Kiowa Indians on their wedding day, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 657)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing next to a tree set piece, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 658)
    - Studio portrait of four American Indian women, one woman posed sitting and three women posed standing, one women posed standing also carries an American Indian child on her back, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 659)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and wearing a buckskin dress with fringe, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 660)
      Inscription in negative: "5"
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian child posed standing between an American Indian man and an American Indian woman posed sitting on the floor, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 661)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian man posed sitting and holding an American Indian child with an American Indian woman posed standing, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 662)
    - Studio portrait of two American Indian girls posed sitting and wearing buckskin dresses with elk teeth decoration, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 663)
    - Studio portrait of three American Indian girls with two girls posed sitting and one girl posed standing and all wearing shawls, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 664)
    - Studio bust portrait of an American Indian boy, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 665)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian girl posed sitting with her hands behind her head and wearing a buckskin dress with fringe, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 666)
    - Studio portrait of a Kiowa Indian boy posed standing and wearing a buckskin suit with fringe and wrapped braids, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 667)
    - Studio portrait of a Kiowa Indian boy posed sitting and wearing a buckskin suit with fringe and wrapped braids, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 668)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian toddler posed standing on a chair and crying, circa 1893-1903; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 9, Folder 669)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian girl posed standing on a chair and wearing a buckskin dress, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 670)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian girl posed standing on a chair and wearing a buckskin dress, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 671)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian boy posed standing and wearing a buckskin suit with fringe, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 672)
    - Studio portrait of a American Indian girl posed standing and wearing a dress with elk teeth decoration, as well as wrapped braids and forelock, and a cross necklace, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 673)
    - Studio portrait of a American Indian girl posed standing and wearing a dress with elk teeth decoration, as well as a cross necklace, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 674)
    - Studio portrait of a American Indian girl posed standing and wearing a dress with elk teeth decoration and fringe; she stands next to a table that holds a toy cradleboard and doll, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 675)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and carrying an American Indian child on her back, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 676)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and carrying an American Indian child on her back, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 677)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and carrying an American Indian child on her back, circa 1893-1903; 3 unmounted photographic prints (Box 9, Folder 678)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing next to a cradleboard resting on a chair that holds an American Indian infant, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 679)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and wearing a cradleboard on her back with a set of antlers resting on the floor in the foreground, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 680)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and wearing a cradleboard on her back with an American Indian toddler, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 681)
    - Studio half portrait of an American Indian woman posed standing and carrying an American Indian child on her back, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 682)
    - Studio portrait of two cradleboards propped against a fence set piece with an American Indian infant visible in one of the cradleboards, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 683)
    - Studio portrait of a cradleboard with an American Indian infant resting on a fur-covered chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 684)
    - Studio portrait of a cradleboard with a sleeping American Indian infant resting on a fur-covered chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 685)
    - Studio portrait of a cradleboard with an American Indian infant resting on a fur-covered chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 686)
    - Studio portrait of a cradleboard with an American Indian infant resting on a chair, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 687)
  - Studio Photographs of American Indian Artifacts
    - Studio photograph of American Indian artifacts, including a bow, arrows, quiver, beaded bag, and calumet, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 688)
    - Studio photograph of an American Indian artifact, probably a shield, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 689)
    - Studio photograph of numbered American Indian artifacts, including clothing, cradleboard, bow, and moccasins, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 690)
    - Studio photograph of an American Indian feathered war bonnet, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 9, Folder 691)
- Texas, circa 1893-1940; Series IX; 1.25; (1 box)
  Series IX is organized into twenty-one subseries: Austin County, Brown County, Dallas, Davis Mountains, Donley County, Edwards County, El Paso County, Fort Bend County, Greer County, Hemphill County, Lampasas County, McCulloch County, Menard County, Mills County, Montague County, Robertson County, San Saba County, Texas Panhandle Region, Texas Panhandle Region, Waller County, and Unidentified Locations in Texas
  This series chiefly consists of landscape views of sites throughout Texas, including ranches. Many images also document deer and fowl hunting parties.
  Portraits of American Indians with identified locations in Indian Territory or Oklahoma Territory are in Series VII.
  - Austin County
    - View of a road lined with trees with Spanish moss and man posed sitting in a horse-drawn buggy near Bellville, Austin County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 692)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Views around Bellville, Tex."
  - Brown County
    - View of field with oil tanker railcars in the distance in Brownwood, Brown County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 693)
      Inscription on the recto of the print: "Oil fields, Brownwood, Texas"
  - Dallas
    - View of the residence of Alexander Sanger in "The Cedars" neighborhood of Dallas, Dallas County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 694)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Sanger's Residence on Ervay Street, Dallas, Tex."
  - Davis Mountains
    - View of a pond in the foreground and a log cabin, wooden building, and tents in the background, identified as the ranch of G. W. Evans in Panther Canyon of the Davis Mountains near Fort Davis, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print and 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 10, Folder 695)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "G. W. Evans's ranch house in the Davis Mts near Ft. Davis"
      An unmounted photographic print has clouds printed into the sky and an inscription in the negative: "Evans Ranch in the Davis Mts. near Ft. Davis, Tex. Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of eight men in a camp with three deer carcasses, as well as horses, a wagon, and a tent in the Davis Mountains near Fort Davis, Texas, 1905 November; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 696)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Hunting party in the Davis Mts near Ft. Davis, Tex."
  - Donley County
    - View of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, sitting in a camp with a dog near a tent and covered wagon in Donley County, Texas, 1894; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 697)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Our camp in Donley Co., Tex., on the north fork of Red River. Just 40 miles from no where."
  - Edwards County
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, holding a rifle and posed standing with a horse carrying three deer carcasses near Paint Creek, Edwards County, Texas, circa 1894; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 698)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "A morning hunt on Paint Creek, West Tex."
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as Dave Jones, holding a rifle and posed sitting with four deer carcasses on the ground near Paint Creek, Edwards County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 2 mounted photographic prints (Box 10, Folder 699)
      Inscription on recto of a mount: "Deer hunting on Paint Creek, Edwards Co., Tex."
      Inscription on recto of a mount: "Slaying deer on Paint Creek, Edwards Co., Tex."
    - View of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, drinking from Paint Creek next to a rifle and deer carcass in Edwards County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 700)
      Inscription in negative: "Deer hunting along Paint Creek, Edwards Co., Tex., Photo by Ed Irwin"
      Inscription on verso: "By Ed Irwin, 1702 E. 1st St., Tucson, Ariz., Picture #14"
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, posed standing and holding a rifle across his shoulders over two deer carcasses, in front of a body of water, probably Paint Creek in Edwards County, Texas, 1896; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored (Box 10, Folder 701)
      Inscription on verso: "Deer hunting in South West Texas, 1896"
  - El Paso County
    - View of a herd of goats and a goat herder, near El Paso, El Paso County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 3 unmounted photographic prints and a 1 photographic postcard (Box 10, Folder 702)
      Inscription in negative: "On the ranches near El Paso, Tex., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of a herd of goats and a goat herder, near El Paso, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print
  - Fort Bend County
    - Exterior portrait of six women and three men, one man holding a rifle on a hillside, probably in Richmond, Fort Bend County, Texas, circa 1893-1903; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 703)
      Ink stamp on recto: "Irwin & Mankins, Richmond, Texas"
  - Greer County
    The Texas State Legislature Greer County created Greer County in February 1860 on land claimed by both Texas and the United States. In the case, United States v. State of Texas, 162 U.S. 1 (1896), the United States Supreme court held that the land belonged to the United States, and it became part of Oklahoma Territory.
    - View of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, cooking over a fire in a camp with a dog, tent, and covered wagon, in Greer County, Texas, 1895; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 704)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Ed and Old Spot getting breakfast, camp in Greer Co., Tex."
  - Hemphill County
    - Exterior portrait of three men, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, an unidentified man, and Dave Jones, posed sitting in a camp by a tent with a dog and the carcasses of an antelope and two deer in Hemphill County, Texas, 1895; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 705)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Our camp in Hemphill Co., Tex. A two days hunt for Ed and Old Spot"
  - Kimble County
    - Exterior portrait of three men, two holding rifles, with a horse and the carcasses of five deer, identified as William Pinkney "Pink" Irwin, William Edward "Ed" Irwin, and Dave Jones in Kimble County, Texas, circa 1894; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 706)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Hunting party in Kimble Co., Tex."
    - View of three deer carcasses hanging in a camp with a covered wagon, as well as two men mounted on horses and holding rifles, identified as William Pinkney "Pink" Irwin and Dave Jones in Kimble County, Texas, circa 1894; 2 mounted photographic prints (Box 10, Folder 707)
      Inscription on recto of a mount: "Scenes around a hunter's camp in Kimble County, Texas"
      Inscription on recto of a mount: "Views in the mountains of West Tex."
    - View of eight deer carcasses lying on the ground in a hunting camp with two men skinning them, identified as William Pinkney "Pink" Irwin and Dave Jones in Kimble County, Texas, circa 1894; 1 mounted photographic print and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 708)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "Guess we'll proceed to peel 'em"
      Inscription in the negative of the unmounted print: "Scene in a hunting camp near Junction City, Tex. Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of a deer carcass laid in the saddle of a horse, as well as two men holding rifles, one mounted on a horse and the other on foot, identified as William Pinkney "Pink" Irwin and Dave Jones in Kimble County, Texas, circa 1894; 1 mounted photographic print and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 709)
      Inscription on recto of mount: "We were hunting deer but now we are hunting camps"
      Inscription in the negative of the unmounted print: "Deer hunting along the Llano Riv., Kimble Co., Tex. Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of five deer carcasses lying on the ground in a hunting camp with two men, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin and Dave Jones, cooking a meal over a fire while another man, identified as William Pinkney "Pink" Irwin, watches them in Kimble County, Texas, circa 1894; 2 mounted photographic prints and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 710)
      Inscription on recto of a mount: "Hunters camp in west Texas"
      Inscription on recto of a mount: "Scene in a hunting camp, preparing a meal, west Texas"
      Inscription in the negative of the unmounted print: "Scene in a hunting camp along the Llano Riv. near Junction City, Tex. Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of two men, identified as William Pinkney "Pink" Irwin and Dave Jones, holding rifles and standing over a deer carcass near two horses in Kimble County, Texas, circa 1894; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 10, Folder 711)